DAVID VARGAS

Port St. Lucie, FL

<u>davidvargash@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-in-da-code/</u> <u>https://davidvargasdev.com/</u>

Qualification Summary

Seasoned software engineer with over 12 years of experience. Has passion for creating and maintaining solid code-bases for integration and reusability. Thrives on following design principles and software architecture patterns. Has high awareness of industry standards in regard to new technologies, solution performance and user experience. David has proven experience leading teams of engineers on and off-shore. Exhibits constant consciousness about user experience and business profits.

Skills Summary

Languages	Javascript, Typescript, C#, Ruby, HTML 5, CSS 3, Java, C++, SQL
Protocols	Rest, GraphQL, JSON-API, SOAP, TCP, Web-sockets
Industries	E-Commerce, Retail, Health-Care, Automotive
Frameworks	ReactJS, Redux, .Net, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Ruby on Rails, Open-Search, Next.JS, Foundation
Testing	React testing library, RSpec, MSW, Jest, Enzyme,
Environments	Visual Studio Code, Intellij, Eclipse, NetBeans, Microsoft Visual Studio, Borland C++ Builder
User experience tools	Datadog, Rollbar, New Relic, Monetate, Tealeaf, Fullstory, Splunk
Version Control	Git, Subversion, TFS
Databases	Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MariaDB
Project Mngmt & UX	SCRUM, Slack, Jira, Trello, Confluence, Figma
Clouds	AWS, Azure

Experience

Unite Us, New York, USA

MAR 2022 – Present

Tech lead | Senior Software engineer

Led a team of engineers focused on building scalable, user-centric search experiences across multiple platforms to connect individuals with social services.

- Led the development of a customer-facing web SAAS application aimed at improving access to social services across multiple regions.
- Delivered full-stack features using **ReactJS**, **Next.js**, **TypeScript**, **JavaScript**, and **Node.js**, ensuring seamless data flow and performance across the application.
- Contributed to backend services built with **Ruby on Rails** and **OpenSearch**, including the platform's core **Search API**, a major driver of business value used across various client workflows.

1

- Designed a modular micro-frontend system using reusable npm packages, allowing teams to ship independently deployable features with consistent patterns.
- Built and maintained a shared UI component library with Storybook, Material UI, and TailwindCSS, improving developer velocity and design consistency.
- Designed and implemented the platform's core frontend experience, enabling users to discover and navigate social programs through an intuitive, accessible interface.
- Managed CI/CD pipelines with GitHub Actions and Jenkins, and oversaw frontend deployments to AWS (S3. CloudFront, Route 53, Cognito), supporting a reliable and scalable release process.
- Worked cross-functionally with product, design, and backend teams to deliver iterative improvements, maintain system stability, and support the growth of a configurable, multi-tenant platform.

Office Depot. Boca Raton, Florida, USA

MAR 2019 – April 2022

Team Lead | Senior Front-End Developer

Lead a team of front-end engineers, in order to design and build a web solution, that will be the center of all search and navigation for the B2B e-commerce platform.

- Architecture design & implementation of API services and front-end applications for the search & browse e-commerce platform.
- Part of the team that created the web app for Print on Demand. Print on Demand is the market lead product for online copies and flyers printing in the USA.
- Lead the front-end application efforts for the business subscriptions platform.
- Designed and developed the solutions using ReactJS, Redux, HTML 5, CSS 3, SASS and other front-end technologies.

ROWriter-TBC Corporation, Juno Beach, Florida, USA Full Stack Developer

October 2016 – February 2019

- Developed a nationwide software update platform (React, .NET) and a POS system integrated with major US tire supplier APIs.
- Built a data import tool for CSV/Excel to SQL (ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework), reducing manual workflows and tech-support costs.

SISTEC S.A, Luanda, Angola

MAR 2014 - MAY 2016

Team Lead

- Design system architecture based on, ASP .Net MVC 5, HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, Entity
- Framework and MS SQL Server.
- Lead and coordinated a team of .Net developers' to build an Enterprise Resources Planning (ERP) system.
- Played a key role in technology selection, project vision and development process, generating early deliverables and a ready-to-sell version of the product in a short time

DATAZUCAR, AZCUBA, Havana, Cuba

SEP 2012 – FEB 2014

Senior developer

- Developed several web systems for Human Resources, Accountant, Transportation and enterprise management.
- Worked as part of an agile team delivering fast results using SCRUM methodology

University of Computer Sciences, La Habana, Cuba

SEP 2008 – AUG 2012

- **NET DEVELOPER | PROFESSOR**
 - Professor of Programming Techniques and Data Structures, used C# and Visual Studio as study tools.
 - Worked as software support engineer creating internal IDE tools for accelerating development process using C#. XML, HTML, CSS and MS SQL, Contributed to secure university's intellectual property by powering the solution with MD5 snapshots, code cipher and obfuscation mechanisms.

Education

University of Computer Sciences, La Habana, Cuba (2009). Bachelor's Degree Engineer in Computer Science

2